<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Scheuerell on home</title>
    <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mark Scheuerell on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Writing and Professional Development for Graduate Students</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/proposal-writing-and-professional-development-for-graduate-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/proposal-writing-and-professional-development-for-graduate-students/</guid>
      <description>Offered Winter quarter
Course overview This class was originally designed to help students prepare research proposals. It has undergone various modifications since its inception, as different instructors have been placed in charge of it, and as the needs of students have changed. The course still includes the development of scientific ideas into coherent proposals, but it now also addresses other forms of communication, and aspects of professional development to help graduate students during and after their time at the University of Washington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/research/time_series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/research/time_series/</guid>
      <description>I work alongside a wide variety of people to help them analyze their data and better understand the underlying drivers of temporal variability. Projects include:
Finding common patterns in stream temperature, nutrient concentration, and fish productivity across multiple streams, rivers, lakes, and oceans;
Estimating the strength and direction of species interactions in aquatic food webs;
Analyzing risks and benefits of ecological portfolios
Much of this work is done in collaboration with Elizabeth &amp;ldquo;Eli&amp;rdquo; Holmes (NOAA) and Eric Ward (NOAA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices in Environmental Data Science</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/best-practices-in-environmental-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/best-practices-in-environmental-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Offered Winter quarter of odd years
Course overview This course will provide an overview of some data science tools and best practices that can be used to create transparent and reproducible workflows when working with environmental data. Students will learn how to translate raw data from field and lab studies into databases and “tidy” digital formats, which can then be used for plotting, statistical analyses, etc. Students will learn how to track the history of file changes (version control), collaborate online with others, and generate “recipes” for re-creating one’s work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food web interactions</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/research/food_webs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/research/food_webs/</guid>
      <description>Through a combination of empirical data collection and statistical modeling, our group is working to understand the flows of energy and nutrients through aquatic food webs. Examples include nearshore fishes in Puget Sound and non-native fishes in Lakes Sammamish and Washington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Time Series Analysis in Fisheries and Environmental Sciences</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/applied-time-series-analysis-in-fisheries-and-environmental-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/applied-time-series-analysis-in-fisheries-and-environmental-sciences/</guid>
      <description>Co-instructors Eli Holmes &amp;amp; Eric Ward
Offered Spring quarter of odd years
Course overview This course is intended to give students an overview of the theory and practical aspects of fitting time series models to fisheries and environmental data. The course will cover topics ranging from autocorrelation and crosscorrelation, autoregressive (AR) and moving average (MA) models, univariate and multivariate state-space models, and estimating model parameters. This course also covers various aspects of assessing model performance and evaluating model diagnostics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Species status assessments</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/research/ssa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/research/ssa/</guid>
      <description>Downward trends in the size and numbers of fishes in the U.S. and Canada have been reported for various species and stocks for over 40 years. However, the patterns are inconsistent among regions and species, in part because estimating these trends has been complicated by disparate data from which to draw inferences, such as varying sampling methods and missing years and locations owing to limits on personnel and funding. Unfortunately, this is often the case for species listed under the Endangered Species Act (ESA) for whom it is particularly important to understand how changes in size and abundance relate to their at-risk status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Ecological and Environmental Data</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/analysis-of-ecological-and-environmental-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/collection/analysis-of-ecological-and-environmental-data/</guid>
      <description>Offered Spring quarter of even years
Course overview This course introduces students to a large class of statistical models commonly used for analyses in ecology and environmental science. These include simple linear models, such as analysis of variance (ANOVA) and regression models, along with Generalized Linear Models (GLMs) that assume non-normal error distributions (e.g., logistic and Poisson regression). Students will learn to distinguish the difference between fixed and random effects, and how to implement them in mixed-effects models such as Generalized Linear Mixed Models (GLMMs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes A A A A A A A A 6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px) Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices in Environmental Data Science</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/blog/fish549/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/blog/fish549/</guid>
      <description>Course website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Writing and Professional Development for Graduate Students</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/blog/fish550/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/blog/fish550/</guid>
      <description>There are five places where you can choose to show social icons. Here is the tl;dr:
site header (set in config.toml), site footer (set in config.toml), homepage (set in content/_index.md), about page in the sidebar (set in content/about/sidebar/index.md), and contact page (set in content/form/contact.md). Read on to learn how to set up your social icons, and how to show/hide them.
Configure social Wherever you end up wanting to show your social icons, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to start by setting up the links in your site config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Writing and Professional Development for Graduate Students</title>
      <link>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/blog/qerm514/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://faculty.washington.edu/scheuerl/blog/qerm514/</guid>
      <description>There are five places where you can choose to show social icons. Here is the tl;dr:
site header (set in config.toml), site footer (set in config.toml), homepage (set in content/_index.md), about page in the sidebar (set in content/about/sidebar/index.md), and contact page (set in content/form/contact.md). Read on to learn how to set up your social icons, and how to show/hide them.
Configure social Wherever you end up wanting to show your social icons, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to start by setting up the links in your site config.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
